# **Muhammad Haleem**

Mobile: +971558545062

Email: haleemanjum786@gmail.com

Skype ID: haleemch140

### **Professional Summary**

Being a Software Engineer I have been involved in analyzing, developing and deploying web, mobile and desktop based software solutions for various domains of business and daily life by using the PHP and Microsoft .net technologies.

Exceptional work experience in fast-paced, deadline-oriented environments with use of industry fashioned process models.

Strong team participation with extensive background; managing and training junior colleagues. Outstanding technical skills; able to quickly learn new concepts and technologies.

#### **Education**

Master's degree, Computer science
 The Islamia University of Bahawalpur (2010 – 2012)

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages: C, C++, C#, ASP.NET, SharePoint, PHP, CSS, HTML, DHTML, JS, jQuery, XML, Ajax, Flex, HTML5, Angular js, Android, iOS Apps Development
- Databases: MySql,MSSQL
- Frameworks: CodeIgniter, symphony, larval, Zend and cake php
- **CMS**:Joomla, Drupal, Open cart, Magento, WordPress (theme development, woocommerce, plugin development).
- Payment Gateways: Paytab, Payfort, Authorize.net, PayPal Checkout, Google Checkout
- WEB Server: LAMP, WAMP, MAMP, Sqlyog
- Operating Systems: Windows Enterprise, Linux, MacBook Pro
- Web services: WSDL, SOAP
- Web Hosting: IIS, Apache, CGI, Domain, DNS, Email, FTP, SSL, SSH, logs
- Others: Web Designing, Office 365, Google Graph APIs,PSD to HTML, WordPress theme
  development, WordPress plugins development, WordPress widgets
  development,joomla modules development ,joomla components development,joomla
  theme development. Magento theming and module development Responsive theme
  development using Bootstrap

 IDE: Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Net beans, Microsoft Visual Studio, Microsoft Word, Svn, GitHub, RESTfull API, JSON / XML/Soap APIs, Basecamp, Time Doctor for software development

#### **Role & Contribution**

- Analysing user requirements
- Investigating new technologies
- Writing and testing code, refining and rewriting it as necessary.
- Developing existing programs by analysing and identifying areas for modification.
- Creating technical specifications
- Maintaining systems by monitoring and correcting software defects
- Working closely with other staff, such as project managers, graphic artists, UX designers, other developers, systems analysts and sales and marketing professionals
- Handled the CMS (Front End programming)/ (Back End programming)
- Iterative testing and code reviews through development of the application.
- Developed the system Unit.
- Integration Testing & debugging.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

I have Overall 10 years' experience in web development. Currently working as a Sr. Software Engineer in Joseph Group from 2018 till present.

Company: Joseph Group Aug 2018 – Present

**URL:** <a href="http://www.josephgroup.ae/">http://www.josephgroup.ae/</a>

**Role:** Being a Sr. Software Engineer in Joseph Group UAE, I am involved in analyzing, design, implementation, database structure, developing and deploying web application in PHP technologies, IBM watson chatbot, Microsoft bot framework etc.

Company: Knowledge Corp LLC

Feb 2015 – Aug 2018

URL: http://kcorp.net/

**Role:** In Knowledge Corp, I have been working as a key resource in development. My core responsibilities comprises of leading the overall development section. I supervise team, I participate in architecture design, core development and assist project manager in task scheduling and client correspondence.

Company: Wholelifetech Sep 2013 – Feb 2015

URL : http://wholelifetech.com/

**Role**: Analysis, design, implementation, database structure and testing Worked as a Web Developer at Wholelifetech using the open source web technologies like Codelgniter,

symphony, larval, WordPress, joomla, Drupal, Opencart, Magento. In this duration, I had a chance to work on variety of projects and products for potential customers.

Company: LEADconcept Sep 2012 – Sep 2013

URL: http://leadconcept.com/

**Role:** As a junior software developer worked on bug fixes, writing and maintaining code for computer applications. Contributing to development team meetings, troubleshooting, patching computer code, and collaborating with other developers to create applications.

## **Projects**

I have more than 60 projects in my list, my latest project list is below.

**Project Name:** The Entertainerme

URL:https://www.theentertainerme.com/

**CMS:** WordPress

The Entertainer, established in 2001, is the leading provider of buy one get one free incentive across the Middle East, Africa, Asia and Europe. With a vast portfolio and a wide selection of quality merchant partners, the Entertainer has something to offer everyone and is regarded as an essential annual purchase for thousands of local residents and tourists.

**Project Name:** Mlifeshopping

URL:http://www.mlifeshopping.com/

**CMS:** Magento

Mlife Shopping has been in business for the last 5 years. We are dedicated to providing the widest selection of merchandise at the most affordable prices, as well as to provide the best service to our valued customers. Mlife Shopping has thousands of products available, and we continue to broaden our inventory periodically. We treat each customer differently as everyone has their own likes and dislikes. Through the years we have discovered that respect and care during the shopping experience and post purchase support is the most important thing. Hence, we at Mlife Shopping strive to ensure the highest level of customer satisfaction for all guests.

Project Name: OLA APP

Production Sizes and Graphics Artwork Requisition

URL: http://psgar.josephgroup.ae

CMS: larval 5.7

A largest Signage Manufacturer in the Middle East & Africa. Build from scratch Management System from adding signage attributes, artworks, quotations, purchase orders, production and dispatch system, notifications and maintain records. Categories include petrol pump signage like canopy, totem, spreader unit, CSU, air & water signs, accessories and spares and others. Develop in Laravel 5.8 & LAMP

**Project Name: Dubai Exports** 

URL:https://exportersgateway.com/

CMS: Drupal 8

Dubai Exports strives to ensure the success of the exports sector in Dubai and the UAE, providing constant guidance, advice and practical support to both overseas buyers and suppliers.

We develop long-term growth strategies to help businesses expand and maximise their opportunities given by Dubai's unique position as a natural trade gateway between the East and the West.

Project Name: Saudi Exports URL: <a href="https://saudiexports.sa">https://saudiexports.sa</a>

CMS: Drupal

The Saudi economic indicators exhibit tangible and spectacular success in which the private sector actively participated. This sector includes companies, institutions, and businessmen with various names, sizes, and capitals. The roles of other sectors in the state should not be overlooked; neither is their quest for reinforcing our national economy and achieving positive results in economic and development fields.

Project Name: jeddah economic gateway

URL:https://jeg.org.sa/

CMS: Drupal

The Jeddah Economic Gateway (JEG) website is one of the websites of the Jeddah Chamber of Commerce and Industry (JCCI) and is managed by the Knowledge Center of the Information and IT Sector. Become the main reference of economic information in the Jeddah region, build a complete and updated economics database about the Jeddah region, Authentication of all economic data that interest the Jeddah business community, Provide economic information such as statistics and studies to decision-makers, academics, researchers, and related parties. Introduce the business community to the latest developments in the various fields of the economy. Easy communication between local and international businesses

#### **Personal Information**

Date of birth :20<sup>th</sup>April 1990
Marital status : Married
Gender : Male
Nationality : Pakistani
Religion : Islam
Current Location : Dubai

Visa Status : Permanent NIC No : 31205-6276826-1

# **Key Competencies**

- Providing innovative new ideas and solutions to problems
- Able to juggle priorities and multiple projects.
- Learning new technologies and keeping abreast of markets developments.
- Participation in various software competitions.

## References

It can be provided if needed.